William Wong, MASc, BASc

william.wai.lim.wong@gmail.com | Toronto, ON

647-762-7892

PROFILE

Ambitious and detailed Mechanical Engineer with experience in die casting, hydraulics, pneumatics, and in other buildings mechanical and electrical systems. A strong team member who brings passion and employment experience in: manufacturing, failure analysis, and project management. Thrive in problem solving and inspired to gain more skills in this area, i.e., problem solving, design, etc.

Knowledge of safety codes and industrial manufacturing standards and competent with various testing processes. Determined to build upon experiences from working in Hong Kong for the past seven years. Open to accelerating my career to expand on my knowledge and practical experience in engineering.

EDUCATION CREDENTIALS

Master of Applied Science (MASc) Aerospace Engineering, Ryerson University, Toronto ON, 2012

Bachelor in Applied Science (BASc) - Honours Mechanical Engineering Co-operative Program University of Waterloo, Waterloo ON, 2004-2009

WORK HISTORY

ASSISTANT ENGINEER

RNB Engineering Hong Kong Limited and Region Fine (HK) Limited, Hong Kong 2016 - March 2019

- Focused on time management and conserving resources for each project recognized by supervisors and managers for efficiencies and practical skills within engineering tasks
- Applied different process to measure and define problems or issues, then providing costeffective solutions that were sustainable. Demonstrated exceptional skills with using solid modelling to provide work-through solutions in a timely manner
- Collaborated with technical staff to design specifications, requirements and works scheduling –
 further drafted English tender documents for maintenance and replacement works of
 mechanical and electrical systems (HVAC, lift and escalator, LVSB, hydrofoil platform) in
 crematoria and ferry terminals of Hong Kong Government
- Coordinated with the manufacturer and local service agent to investigate the cause of early failure of equipment and discrepancy of recommended service life in maintenance manual, developed solutions to improve service life of equipment to comply with original contract requirements
- Assisted the Senior Engineer in the Electrical and Mechanical Services Department to analyse SCADA (Supervisory Control and Data Acquisition) event log with technical grade staff working toward common goals to identify errors within the programming structure; drafted the confidential investigation report that was presented to the Mechanical Working Group and Trading Services Management Committee

ENGINEERING SUPERVISOR

LK Machinery International Limited, Hong Kong and Shenzhen

2012 - 2016

 Provided technical support to overseas customer service and sales department focused on optimizing efficiency and user-friendliness, coordination of multi-disciplinary teams, and developing solutions that were verified with AutoCAD and Solidworks to update schedules and instruction manuals LK Machinery International Limited continued ...

- Revised the entire AutoCAD drawing set and instruction manual based on customer requirements in order to receive the final installment payment as per contract. This included 21 machines delivered throughout a 5-year project
- Participated in machine assembly and testing phase, checked machine design and control interlock complied with all safety regulations and codes, and ensured all machine functions met contract requirements and all defects were corrected
- Analyzed machine failure problems with the use of 3D modelling and FEA (Finite Element Analysis) to determine root cause of failures and incorrect applications of die casting
- Performed engineering calculations on design specifics to verify and query the engineering design team to provide solutions that were cost effective and sustainable

Co-op Placements:

Quality Impact Team -Teleflex Power Systems, Kitchener ON

• Created a record of returned failed CNG pressure regulators, analyzed failures and conducted investigations to identify source of failure from surveying supplier parts to production process

Product Development Engineering - Progressive Moulded Products Limited, Concord ON

 Created prototypes of plastic moulded parts to address issues identified by customer and set up test fixtures and evaluated prototype designs to troubleshoot and resolve problems

Lean Manufacturing Engineering - Fenwick Automotive Products, Toronto ON

 Developed standard work instructions and videos for manufacturing work stations to improve productivity and quality control. Studied proposed changes to individual production stages making suggestions to improve and enhance production metrics and processes

Engineering Student - TRW Occupant Safety Systems Canada Limited, Midland ON

 Designed accessories for plant equipment for improved ergonomics and advanced worker safety. Solved and addressed day-to-day worker safety related problems raised by the health and safety committee through discussions and implementation of agreed upon solutions. Planned and executed modifications involving plant equipment for increased productivity.

Assistant Project Manager - Public Works and Government Services Canada Parliamentary Precinct Directorate, Ottawa ON

 Performed various administrative duties including preparing minutes of meetings and changes to contracts and job orders. Monitored progress on construction projects for government offices and buildings and then further communicated any needed information to stakeholders.

Research Analyst - Caneta Research Inc., Mississauga ON

• Gathered building envelope information and energy reducing measures for simulation of daily building energy use and compared with benchmark building to determine energy savings.